<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Education Site (ver 1)</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Education Site (ver 1)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>First introductory video</title>
      <link>/videos/1_introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/videos/1_introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These two videos are the first in the Computer Technology educational series by Soloman Arminius. An attempt is made to keep them around five minutes long.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second introductory video</title>
      <link>/videos/2_introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/videos/2_introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the second of two first-draft videos of the first in the Computer Technology educational series by Soloman Arminius.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 2: Mobile Devices and Workstations</title>
      <link>/videos/3_mobile_and_workstation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/videos/3_mobile_and_workstation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Episode 2 of the Computers, Cyber, and Technology series. This episode is focused on components of mobile devices and modern workstations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Written with Hugo This site is created using Hugo to generate a static site that is hosted on GitHub and duplicated in IPFS and deep web (web 3.0) locations.
Written in Go, Hugo is an open source static site generator available under the Apache Licence 2.0. Hugo supports TOML, YAML and JSON data file types, Markdown and HTML content files and uses shortcodes to add rich content. Other notable features are taxonomies, multilingual mode, image processing, custom output formats, HTML/CSS/JS minification and support for Sass SCSS workflows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/lpic/exam-010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/lpic/exam-010/</guid>
      <description>This is a local reconstruction of LPI&amp;rsquo;s LPIC-1 content.
Topic 1: The Linux Community and a Career in Open Source 1.1 Linux Evolution and Popular Operating Systems Description: Knowledge of Linux development and major distributions. Key Knowledge Areas:  Distributions Embedded Systems Linux in the Cloud  The following is a partial list of the used files, terms and utilities: - Debian, Ubuntu (LTS) - CentOS, openSUSE, Red Hat, SUSE - Linux Mint, Scientific Linux - Raspberry Pi, Raspbian - Android  1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/lpic/exam-201/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/lpic/exam-201/</guid>
      <description>This is a local reconstruction of LPI&amp;rsquo;s LPIC-2 content.
Topic 200: Capacity Planning 200.1 Measure and Troubleshoot Resource Usage Description: Candidates should be able to measure hardware resource and network bandwidth, identify and troubleshoot resource problems. Key Knowledge Areas: - Measure CPU usage - Measure memory usage - Measure disk I/O - Measure network I/O - Measure firewalling and routing throughput - Map client bandwidth usage - Match / correlate system symptoms with likely problems - Estimate throughput and identify bottlenecks in a system including networking  The following is a partial list of the used files, terms and utilities: - iostat - netstat - w - top - sar - processes blocked on I/O - blocks out - vmstat - pstree, ps - Isof - uptime - swap - blocks in  200.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/lpic/exam-202/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/lpic/exam-202/</guid>
      <description>This is a local reconstruction of LPI&amp;rsquo;s LPIC-2 content.
Topic 207: Domain Name Server 207.1 Basic DNS server configuration Description: Candidates should be able to configure BIND to function as a caching-only DNS server. This objective includes the ability to manage a running server and configuring logging. Key Knowledge Areas: - BIND 9.x configuration files, terms and utilities - Defining the location of the BIND zone files in BIND configuration files - Reloading modified configuration and zone files - Awareness of dnsmasq, djbdns and PowerDNS as alternate name servers  The following is a partial list of the used files, terms and utilities: - /etc/named.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/lpic/exam-300/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/lpic/exam-300/</guid>
      <description>Topic 390: OpenLDAP Configuration 390.1 OpenLDAP Replication Description: Candidates should be familiar with the server replication available with OpenLDAP. Key Knowledge Areas: - Replication concepts - Configure OpenLDAP replication - Analyze replication log files - Understand replica hubs - LDAP referrals - LDAP sync replication  The following is a partial list of the used files, terms and utilities: - master / slave server - multi-master replication - consumer - replica hub - one-shot mode - referral - syncrepl - pull-based / push-based synchronization - refreshOnly and refreshAndPersist - replog  390.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/lpic/exam-303/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/lpic/exam-303/</guid>
      <description>Topic 325: Cryptography 325.1 X.509 Certificates and Public Key Infrastructures Description: Candidates should understand X.509 certificates and public key infrastructures. They should know how to configure and use OpenSSL to implement certification authorities and issue SSL certificates for various purposes. Key Knowledge Areas: - Understand X.509 certificates, X.509 certificate lifecycle, X.509 certificate fields and X.509v3 certificate extensions - Understand trust chains and public key infrastructures - Generate and manage public and private keys - Create, operate and secure a certification authority - Request, sign and manage server and client certificates - Revoke certificates and certification authorities  The following is a partial list of the used files, terms and utilities: - openssl, including relevant subcommands - OpenSSL configuration - PEM, DER, PKCS - CSR - CRL - OCSP  325.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/lpic/exam-304/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/lpic/exam-304/</guid>
      <description>Topic 330: Virtualization 330.1 Virtualization Concepts and Theory Description: Candidates should know and understand the general concepts, theory and terminology of Virtualization. This includes Xen, KVM and libvirt terminology. Key Knowledge Areas: - Terminology - Pros and Cons of Virtualization - Variations of Virtual Machine Monitors - Migration of Physical to Virtual Machines - Migration of Virtual Machines between Host systems - Cloud Computing  The following is a partial list of the used files, terms and utilities: - Hypervisor - Hardware Virtual Machine (HVM) - Paravirtualization (PV) - Container Virtualization - Emulation and Simulation - CPU flags - /proc/cpuinfo - Migration (P2V, V2V) - IaaS, PaaS, SaaS  330.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>